Contact

kevinsilveira6@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kevinsilveira6 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing

Healthcare Management
Healthcare Information Technology

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Subspecialty Certification in Cardiac Surgery (CSC)

Subspecialty Certification in Cardiac Medicine (CMC)

Certified Correctional Health Professional (CCHP)

Nurse Manager Certificate

Adult Critical-Care Nurse Certification (CCRN)

Kevin A. Silveira, MBA, RN, CCHP, CCRN-CMC-CSC, PHN

Health Services Administrator at Wellpath

Visalia, California Area

Summary

Health Services Administrator with high-level experience in community, governmental, and academic medical center environments. Working to use my extensive knowledge and demonstrated outcomes in the areas of patient care delivery, employee satisfaction and engagement, evidence-based staff development, and leadership to provide outstanding services to our community.

Experience

Wellpath

2 years 4 months

Health Services Administrator March 2019 - Present (1 year 4 months)

36650 Road 112, Visalia, CA 93291

Health Services Administrator - Tulare County

- Maintains overall administrative responsibility for all on-site and off-site health care services for all of Tulare County's adult and juvenile detention facilities.
- Responsible for planning, developing, and directing the overall operation of all five detention facilities in Tulare County to ensure they follow all standards, local, state, and federal regulations
- Coordinates the health care services for the county's detention facilities in collaboration with the Tulare County Health and Human Services Agency, Sheriff, and Probation Department.

Director of Nursing June 2018 - March 2019 (10 months)

36650 Road 112 Visalia, CA 93291

Director of Nursing - Tulare County

Responsible for planning, developing, and directing the overall operation
of the Nursing Department in compliance with all standards, local, state and
federal regulations and laws

- Assists in the overall responsibility for coordinating the health care services for the county's detention facilities and carries out the terms of the county contract
- Assists in the recruitment, hiring, training, and supervision of all personnel
- Collaborates with Medical Director on clinical issues and policy changes

Nursing Supervisor

March 2018 - June 2018 (4 months)

36650 Road 112 Visalia, CA 93291

Nursing Supervisor - Tulare County

- Directly supervised one shift and shared 24-hour responsibility for all nursing and paraprofessional personnel
- Scheduled evaluation conferences for non-supervisory nursing personnel and participated in their performance evaluations on a regularly scheduled basis
- Prepared and submitted daily, monthly and annual medical records and reports

Kaiser Permanente

1 year 3 months

Registered Nurse - Ambulatory Care

March 2018 - September 2018 (7 months)

Fresno Medical Center, 7300 N Fresno St, Fresno, CA 93720

Per-Diem Staff Nurse - Adult Medicine

• Provided patient care for Adult, Family, and Internal Medicine patients in all of Kaiser Permanente's Fresno locations

Registered Nurse - ICU

July 2017 - March 2018 (9 months)

South Sacramento Medical Center, 6600 Bruceville Road, Sacramento, CA 95823

Per-Diem Staff Nurse - 24-bed ICU

 Provided patient care for critically-ill Medical, Neuro, Surgical, Cardiology, and Trauma patients

Community Medical Centers

Registered Nurse - CVICU

August 2014 - March 2018 (3 years 8 months)

Community Regional Medical Center - Fresno, 2823 Fresno St, Fresno, CA 93721

Staff Nurse - 12-bed CVICU

- Provided patient care for Cardiac Surgery, Vascular Surgery, Cardiac Medicine, Interventional Cardiology, and Heart Failure/Ventricular Assist Device clients
- Unit-based Cardiac Surgery Advanced Life Support and ECMO leadership projects
- CVICU Practice Council member

Adventist Medical Center - Hanford Registered Nurse - ICU April 2012 - August 2014 (2 years 5 months)

Adventist Medical Center - Hanford, 115 Mall Drive Hanford, CA 93230

Staff Nurse - 22-bed ICU

- Provided patient care for critically-ill Medical and Surgical patients
- Participated in unit-based Alarm Fatigue initiative

Adventist Health
Radiology Clerical Lead
December 2008 - January 2010 (1 year 2 months)

Central California Imaging Center, 115 Mall Drive Hanford, CA 93230

- Supervised daily operations, actively assisted and provided direction to front office and scheduling staff as required
- · B3 Shining Star Award recipient

Education

University of North Dakota

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Nursing - Rural Health and Rural

Populations · (2020 - 2023)

California State University, Fresno

Master of Business Administration - MBA, Business Administration and

Management, General · (2017 - 2018)

California State University, Bakersfield

Bachelors of Science in Nursing, RN-BSN Program · (2013 - 2014)

College of the Sequoias
Associate of Science in Nursing, Registered Nursing · (2007 - 2011)